HARSHDEEP SINGH

https://dhillonempire.me/

Highlights

- ★ A recent graduate from BCIT School of Computing and Academic Studies
- ★ Highly ambitious and passionate self-learner
- ★ Project experience in JavaScript, React, and React Native

Technical Skills

Languages	Tools	Libraries/Frameworks	SQA	uı/ux
HTML/CSS	Slack	React/Angular	Automated testing	Wireframing
JavaScript/TypeScript	Jira	React Native/Ionic	Writing test cases	Prototyping
Python	Git	Node.js	Documenting reports	Usability Testing
C#/ASP.NET	Trello	Express		

Project Experience

★ Portfolio Website

- Created a static site using React and Gatsby and deployed on Netlify
- Integrated icons and graphics from third party libraries such as font awesome and feather icons into React components
- Utilized third party forms to create 'contact' page
- Set up custom CI/CD pipelines to automatically deploy when source code is updated

★ React Native Game (Course Project)

March 2020 - April 2020

- Created 2048 game in react native
- o Integrated Google authentication API to allow users to sign in
- Used 'react native animatable' to add animations

★ ReactJS calculator (Personal Project)

October 2020 - November 2020

- Wire-framed calculator UI grid using Figma
- o Animated the interface of the calculator to enhance user experience

Work Experience

★ Zeniox, Montréal, QB

May 2020 - September 2020

Technical Support Agent (Full Time, remote)

- Rapidly devised solutions to technical problems/difficulties faced by non technical end users via telephone, email, and chat
- Gained experience communicating with end users of various backgrounds
- Provide daily support to users of various computer systems including answering questions, analyzing problems, and quickly forming solutions to return systems to proper operation

★ Xorosoft Inc, Burnaby, BC

May 2019 - April 2020

Junior Software Developer (Technical Intern)

- Identified customer needs and helped customers use specific features of an ERP software (SaaS)
- Participated in pair-programming to work on bug fixes
- Engaged with intermediate/senior developers to learn the codebase and development environment

Education

★ British Columbia Institute of Technology

January 2019 - December 2020

Computer Information Technology (Post Secondary Diploma)

- Full-Stack Web Development
- UI/UX Designing
- Database Administration
- Algorithms and Data Structures
- Mobile Application Development

Hackathons

★ cuHacking January 2021

- The goal was to build a system to collect data from multiple sensor cameras to study the behaviour of animals (under lab conditions) that enabled us to remotely start/stop sensors through a web interface, improve data sharing and collect data in sync from multiple sensors
- Developed the Front-End of the website using React and Bootstrap libraries
- Our team of 4 won the prize for 'Best Hardware Hack'

★ NASA Space Apps COVID-19 Challenge

May 2020

 Worked in a team of 6 on hacking for the COVID-19 pandemic where we used the NASA satellite data to plot the green land (parks in our case) and based on algorithms, the program outputs a "risk-rating" number that marks the risk percentage for different parks ★ Vanhacks October 2019

 Created an offline accessible progressive web app using react and gatsby for linkvan.ca, an initiative to make food, shelter and other resources more available to the homeless population of Vancouver

o Learnt about service-workers and processing json data in React